<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://klinjin.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://klinjin.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2025-11-05T22:48:58+00:00</updated><id>https://klinjin.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>A simple, whitespace theme for academics. Based on [*folio](https://github.com/bogoli/-folio) design. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">some art works</title><link href="https://klinjin.github.io/blog/2024/images/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="some art works"/><published>2024-11-27T21:01:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-11-27T21:01:00+00:00</updated><id>https://klinjin.github.io/blog/2024/images</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://klinjin.github.io/blog/2024/images/"><![CDATA[<p>Some art projects.</p> <h3 id="oil-painting">oil painting</h3> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/6_CHOICE_%E5%89%AF%E6%9C%AC-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/6_CHOICE_%E5%89%AF%E6%9C%AC-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/6_CHOICE_%E5%89%AF%E6%9C%AC-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/6_CHOICE_%E5%89%AF%E6%9C%AC.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/Image_%E5%89%AF%E6%9C%AC-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/Image_%E5%89%AF%E6%9C%AC-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/Image_%E5%89%AF%E6%9C%AC-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/Image_%E5%89%AF%E6%9C%AC.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <h3 id="red-eyes">red eyes</h3> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/IMG_3603_%E5%89%AF%E6%9C%AC.JPG" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/IMG_3603_%E5%89%AF%E6%9C%AC.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="lazy" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/IMG_3604_%E5%89%AF%E6%9C%AC.JPG" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/IMG_3604_%E5%89%AF%E6%9C%AC.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="lazy" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/IMG_3801-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/IMG_3801-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/IMG_3801-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/IMG_3801.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="lazy" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <h3 id="colored-pencils">colored pencils</h3> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/IMG_4357-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/IMG_4357-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/IMG_4357-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/IMG_4357.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="lazy" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/IMG_8631%203-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/IMG_8631%203-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/IMG_8631%203-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/IMG_8631%203.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="lazy" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/IMG_0362%202-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/IMG_0362%202-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/IMG_0362%202-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/IMG_0362%202.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="lazy" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/IMG_3760_edited_%E5%89%AF%E6%9C%AC-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/IMG_3760_edited_%E5%89%AF%E6%9C%AC-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/IMG_3760_edited_%E5%89%AF%E6%9C%AC-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/IMG_3760_edited_%E5%89%AF%E6%9C%AC.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="lazy" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/%E5%9B%BE%E7%89%876_%E5%89%AF%E6%9C%AC-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/%E5%9B%BE%E7%89%876_%E5%89%AF%E6%9C%AC-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/%E5%9B%BE%E7%89%876_%E5%89%AF%E6%9C%AC-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/%E5%9B%BE%E7%89%876_%E5%89%AF%E6%9C%AC.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="lazy" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="arts"/><category term="art"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[this is a page of my drawings/paintings]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How the structure of Arcadia Resembles a Fractal</title><link href="https://klinjin.github.io/blog/2023/arcadia/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How the structure of Arcadia Resembles a Fractal"/><published>2023-03-18T16:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-03-18T16:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://klinjin.github.io/blog/2023/arcadia</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://klinjin.github.io/blog/2023/arcadia/"><![CDATA[<p>Tom Stoppard’s play <em>Arcadia</em> <d-cite key="arcadia"></d-cite> has a remarkable feature of its temporal structure intertwining the past and the present in the same space. It challenges the conventional time sequence of narration and also employs its unique stage settings, as described elaborately at the start of Scene Two (Stoppard 19), that “both periods must share the state of the room, without the additions and subtractions.” These characteristics contribute to the play’s overall structure as a composition of both resemblances and variances which can be related to the mathematical concept of fractals. In this paper, we will explore how the fractal structure is manifested and what’s the intention behind this design.</p> <p>The discussion on how the relationship between science and nature first shows up in Scene 1, when Thomasina questioned if God is a Newtonian and how the formula must exist for all the future of every atom. Her tutor, Septimus, raised the defects of the argument by mentioning free will, God’s will, and sin but was eventually persuaded by Thomasina (Stoppard 10). This discussion was interrupted by Charter and later brought up in Scene 3 that “nature is written in numbers” (Stoppard 41). Thomasina’s dubiety on</p> <p>why all the equations can only describe the shapes of manufacture leads her to a beginning theory about chaotic shapes in nature. Her attempt to plot the leaf and deduce its equation was later identified by Hannah and Valentine as an iterated algorithm to plot in a way that “each graph is a small section of the previous one, blown up” (Stoppard 48). This is a fractal that exhibits self-similarity on increasingly smaller scales.<d-cite key="fractal"></d-cite> (Gouyet) This way of modeling the irregularities of nature is interpreted by Valentine as plotting a picture of turbulence: “growth—change—creation” (Stoppard 51). We need fractals because “the future is disorder” (Stoppard 52). This direct reference to fractals introduces a scientific context to the play which connects the early nineteenth century and the present day when both discuss the applications of fractals, one is for plotting a leaf and the other is to calculate the grouse numbers. It also reveals the point of view of Stoppard on fractals and hence is helpful for us to relate the play’s fractal structure to grander themes.</p> <p>Now with the concepts of fractals elucidated, we can look into the places where the structure of fractals manifests throughout the play. Apart from the fractals theory itself recurring throughout the play, the storylines of two different time periods also reflect the idea that patterns can repeat at different scales, creating complex and unpredictable systems like a fractal. For example, in Scene 2, Bernard asserted that the poet Charter was killed in a duel with Lord Byron, which is refuted by our knowledge that Charter didn’t manage to have a duel with Septimus and further detailed in the following scene when we go back in time that Charter succeeded in challenging Septimus to a duel. This magnification of details on the same subject is the exact feature of a fractal. The same is</p> <p>in Scene 5, in which Bernard was connecting Byron with the critic of Charter’s work and the note that suggested an affair with Mrs. Charter found in Byron’s possession of Charter’s book (Stoppard 59) with his made-up “lost but ineradicable letter” written by Byron to Septimus (Stoppard 61), the complexity of the notes and letters that the present day characters used as evidence was later revealed in Scene 6, and so is the myth of Charter’s death. There was indeed a burned, lost letter written by Byron to Septimus that was “never to be read by a living soul” (Stoppard 75) and Byron was also found out to have an affair with Mrs. Charter (Stoppard 72). But, Charter’s death is unrelated to Lord Byron as his identity as the botanist who died from a monkey bite was revealed. The recurring elements in both the present’s deduction and the past’s truth form a sense of certainty out of disorder coupled with the unpredictability of what already happened and is counted as history. The complex patterns that construct the chaos and confusion of information resemble the complexity in a fractal.</p> <p>What really pushes the play to a climax is in Scene 7, where both time periods coexist on the stage, showing the interwoven structure visually to the audience. The switch back and forth in time becomes faster and faster and reaches its maxima when Lady Croom and Chloe, two characters in two different timelines, were entering and exiting the room at the same time looking for a missing person, leading to the “unendurable noise” and chaos (Stoppard 86-87). The end of the play shows three couples on the stage at the same time — Thomasina and Septimus, Chloe and Bernard, and Hannah and Gus — again contributing to the self-similarity feature of different scales. This final scene’s coexistence of different time periods visually displays Stoppard’s theory of underlying orders in unpredictable randomness by creating a sense of chaos while maintaining patterns in characters and settings. The fractal’s expanding symmetry at various scales (Gouyet) is hence manifested in such a way.</p> <p>The intention behind this structure may be referred back to the concepts of fractals. Since fractals are mathematical models to simulate “how nature creates itself” (Stoppard 51), attempting to mathematically regulate and explain future randomness. This overall structure of a fractal relates to the sense of incompleteness of truth and history as more details with similar patterns would emerge and challenge the view of the previous more distant scale. Fractals also give rise to a sense of repetition and interconnectedness that unite the two time periods in all ways. With the constant noise and confusion in plots and characters, we see characters probing for different answers with the inevitable loss and errors of information, but as Hannah said “it’s wanting to know that makes us matter” (Stoppard 80), the effort to understand what’s assured to be unpredictable is what fractals are created for— the determinism in disorder. Hence, <em>Arcadia</em> offers an optimistic view on our doomed fate (Stoppard 69) to be cold to death (Stoppard 82) that studying our history still helps us to figure out complex patterns out of increasing chaos and this inquiry of knowing that embraces uncertainties is what sustains us to create a given scaled window of order and meanings.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="literature"/><category term="clit&amp;sci"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Tom Stoppard’s play Arcadia has a remarkable feature of its temporal structure intertwining the past and the present in the same space. It challenges the conventional time sequence of narration and also employs its unique stage settings, as described elaborately at the start of Scene Two (Stoppard 19), that “both periods must share the state of the room, without the additions and subtractions.” These characteristics contribute to the play’s overall structure as a composition of both resemblances and variances which can be related to the mathematical concept of fractals. In this paper, we will explore how the fractal structure is manifested and what’s the intention behind this design.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Maxwell’s Demon in Pynchon and Kesey’s books</title><link href="https://klinjin.github.io/blog/2023/maxwell-demon/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Maxwell’s Demon in Pynchon and Kesey’s books"/><published>2023-02-19T16:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-02-19T16:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://klinjin.github.io/blog/2023/maxwell-demon</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://klinjin.github.io/blog/2023/maxwell-demon/"><![CDATA[<p>Thomas Pynchon’s The Crying of Lot 49 <d-cite key="pynchon"></d-cite> and Ken Kesey’s Demon Box <d-cite key="kesey"></d-cite> both explore the Second Law of Thermodynamics <d-cite key="maxwell"></d-cite> and its accompanying thought experiment of a demon sorting out fast and slow particles at the divider in a box. This notion of Maxwell’s Demon however implies distinct social and personal meanings in each work but both influence the protagonists’ perceptions of reality. In this paper, I will explore the implicit meanings behind the Demon and how they are manifested in terms of the psychological evolution of the two characters.</p> <h2 id="the-demon">The Demon</h2> <p>In The Crying of Lot 49, the Demon first appears in Chapter 2 (Pynchon 68) and was described as a mental sorting mechanism. After she physically experimented with the machine and failed to connect with the Demon, she realized herself doing the same job as the Demon or John Nefastis’s machine, which only deals with two parties “thermodynamics and informational”, while she was “faced with a metaphor of God knew how many parts … with coincidences blossoming these days wherever she looked.”</p> <p>(Pynchon 87) In a multi-dimensional correlated system like this, Oedipa tried to “hold [a sound, a word, Trystero] together”, integrating all pieces of knowledge she have to sort out the connections and meanings. To Oedipa or Pynchon, the Demon is for sorting out orders. In Kesey’s Demon Box, the Demon was described more anthropomorphically. With the same sorting job, the Demon becomes a demon-slave who would need food, light and education and more expenses (Kesey 331). The Demon’s job was complemented with “He must deliberate over everything.” (Kesey 332) which makes him hungry and eventually leads to doom for “the nonavailability of energy” (Kesey 323). To Kesey, the Demon is for eating up all the energy.</p> <h2 id="live-in-two-sides-of-the-box">Live in two sides of the box</h2> <p>With different personas of Demon in the two works, the protagonists experience the “two sides of the box” on different levels. Dr. Woofer in Demon Box analogized the thermal box with the “cognitive process of Modern civilization” (Kesey 331) His conversation with Devlin after the therapy workshop concluded that the society is facing a fear of emptiness (Kesey 334), running out of energy because of the consumption of the Demon and irreversibly increasing entropy. The fear of emptiness is related to the search for temporary solutions, such as the use of drugs to achieve a sense of happiness — “high-powered tranquilizers! pain-killers! mood elevators! muscle relaxants! psycho delics!” (Kesey 362). Devlin peeked into these two sides of the box in the scene at Disney land. One side is this father of the poor family who cannot afford another ride for the kids. Despite that we only see him from the back, the body gestures — “sat without comment, not moving, … , gripping the back of the seat” — shows his uneasiness as a working-class dad. Devlin realized the situation of the father and pitied him with the knowledge of the Demon who as well tries hard to “keep a grip” and yet it’s “getting harder all the time”. Devlin had a topdown view in the scene and thought “something was wrong somewhere.” (Kesey 354) There’s the other side of the happy hippos and Disney World. The exhibition of an experiment on drugged hippos presented that the hippos were much “happier” and quelled the attempts to escape. The arguments among the kids on the car and the illusion of Disney as the happiest place in the world prove the appealing concept of happiness to people even though it’s a huge industrial scam, like what they did on the hippos. This, however, is argued as the temporary solution to fight against the entropy or fear of emptiness as condemned by Dr. Woofer at the conference, and Devlin subconsciously realized that he “joined the happy hippos” for his senses are not brought in the present (Kesey 362). We will see trails of his lack of presence later.</p> <p>Oedipa experienced another two sides of the box. On her journey of searching the story that happened in 1853, she experienced this seizure that she might not be left with only “compiled memories of clues … but never the central truth itself” (Pynchon 76). This “central truth” would “destroy its own message irreversibly” and leave enigmatic piles of information like what Oedipa was gathering. She sensed the boundary of these preexisting two realities of “central truth” and pieces of information that would get her nowhere with the metaphor of a seizure: “she would never know how many time such a seizure may already have visited, to how to grasp it should it visit again.” (Pynchon 76) She is looming out of one space while being aware of the other. In this view, the solution to overcome entropy or the nonsense of information is to seek out truth.</p> <h2 id="the-pre-demon-reality">The pre-Demon reality</h2> <p>While both characters are aware of the double-sided world and the operation of the Demon to overcome the growing entropy, they bore the knowledge on personal levels with distinct life philosophies. While Oedipa is relatively optimistic, collecting all the information and searching actively for the truth, she was hindered by the blurred edges between “real and dreamed” at the point she saw the post horn sign everywhere in the city. The summit amount of information she perceived challenged her ethics that “each clue that comes is supposed to have its own clarity, its fine chance for permanence” (Pynchon 95). Even though she was pushing herself to catch everything as clues that lead to the central truth that is meant to be stable and permanent, her reality was challenged by the thought that it would be easier to submit to the dream-like fragments. Compared to her former under-control life as a housewife with a boring rudderless husband, she started to feel instability and irreversibility of decay in her life, yet she still told herself “she was meant to remember” (Pynchon 95) to stay grounded and collected.</p> <p>In contrast, Devlin didn’t have any grip on his reality. As a fantasy novelist, he was constantly not present. The comments of the doctor on his fascination and the scene when he visited the hospital, the stares from the patients “gave [him] a very curious feeling”, which he could not decode and felt something was needed from him but don’t know what it is — “maybe it was just information” (Kesey 339)— all lead t0 his indeterministic reality. His method is to numb the feelings and “keep ahead of the thing” (Kesey 364) with the irresponsible reality of too much drinking and drugs.</p> <h2 id="the-post-demon-reality-challenged-by-the-demon">The post-Demon reality: challenged by the Demon</h2> <p>In the end, the Demon will lose to the second law of thermodynamics. Both Oedipa and Devlin stopped trusting themselves and entered the other realm startled, awakening, and unhinged. For Oedipa, when she realized everything leads to nowhere but swirls back to Pierce Inverarity, she got stuck in a state of paranoia and could no longer tell if every piece of information she tried to track down to the core is a hallucination or truly communicating a message. She has this back-and-forth conversation with herself: “Either you have stumbled … onto a secret richness and concealed density of dream; onto a network…; maybe even onto a real alternative to the existlessness, … or you are hallucinating it …” (Pynchon 141) This obscurity of what is reality and what is hallucination incites her self-doubt and all her former efforts look like running in an “existless” box — the closed thermodynamic system that everything has doomed fate. She became fractured, existing in multi-dimensional spaces of different correlations between realities, but she didn’t overcome the entropy, she was rushed over by the particles — all the mysteries and stories leading back to Pierce — and that broke down her own integrated reality — the life with “absence of surprise” (Pynchon 141). She was cornered to take the paranoia as the reality and the reality as a hallucination.</p> <p>Devlin, too, was hit by the Demon’s conviction for breaking the rule of reversing entropy. He, on contrary, was dragged down to the ground and faced the reality that he was a terrible father, son, and friend (Kesey 369). A sense of guilt occupied him in the last scene when he realized he forgot to bring anything from Disney for his son as he promised and he didn’t call his mother: “It only clarified the fearful murk that had been nagging me into something far more haunting: guilt.” (Kesey 369) This nagging feeling corresponds to the previous “curious feeling” (Kesey 339). This conversion from paralysis to despair leads Devlin to explore the reason behind it, then he concluded that the thing that had been chaining him back is “ the bleak and bottomless rock of failure” (Kesey 369) which dated back to the hot tub’s “black water”, relating back to the notion of the second law of thermodynamics — the doomed using up of energy. He now has the epiphany that he has been numbing himself to not become Maxwell’s Demon to face the destined catastrophe of life. His numbness and fascination now became his attestations of the “morbid self-recrimination” for the belief of “I couldn’t do anything about anything.” (Kesey 369) His self-preservation of floating above reality was broken down, and thus he was finally able to be in the present.</p> <p>In the two contexts, some avoided becoming the Demon and collided with the inevitability of calamity in life, some were pursuing the Demon’s obligation of sorting but were fractured by the multi-level facts. Both had their prior perception of realities challenged, and none escaped this irreversible process of death that dwelled in every single cell of everything. However, we should still appreciate the present and the people around us instead of getting too attached and enchanted to the two-sided closed box, as learned from Devlin’s guilt and Oedipa’s paranoia.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="literature"/><category term="clit&amp;sci"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[How the realities of Oedipa and Devlin are challenged by the Demon]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Poems | Portfolio</title><link href="https://klinjin.github.io/blog/2023/poems-portfolio/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Poems | Portfolio"/><published>2023-02-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-02-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://klinjin.github.io/blog/2023/poems--portfolio</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://klinjin.github.io/blog/2023/poems-portfolio/"><![CDATA[]]></content><author><name></name></author></entry></feed>